renu.ezhil@gmail.com

7+ years of experience in Software Industry. Strong in development and deliverable. Experience in working deadline-oriented environments. Have Sound Knowledge on development, querying and transforming data, bugfixing and deployment. Exceptional written & oral communications skills conveying complex topics in an understandable manner.

Sharing knowledge to team members. Having sound experiences in Implementation, support and roll outprojects. Having experience in enhancement methodologies, Interfaces, Performance tuning.

## **EXPERIENCE AND TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

Technical Expertise	Experience	Description
MuleSoft	5 Months	Mule ESB, API Management, Cloud-hub and continuous integration
DataWeave	5 Months	Designed for transforming data.
.Net Technology	4+ Years.	Worked in various .Net technologies from windows to web. Good knowledge and experience in Design to IIS deployment of a project in .Net and MVC.
Angular (v6)	2 Years.	Worked in Angular (v6) client side framework using the following concept. Events, Forms, Input, Validation, Export Excel, Partial Load (Insert, Update and Deleted), Http, npm and more. Develop a Single Page Application inAngular JS v1.x and v5, Ag- Grid.
Node JS	6 Months.	Worked the automation project for implementing CRUD operation in JIRA using Node JS.
SQL Server	2+ Years.	Operations DML/DDL/DCL etc
MySQL	1 Years	Includes creating/optimizing DML/DDL/DCL etc.
AJAX	1 Years.	Dynamic web display as per data request byclient from server.

### **Primary Skills**

### Web Technologies:

ASP .NET, Ajax, JQuery and Java Script, Web API and Services, Angular, Node JS

### Languages:

C#, VB.

#### **Editor and IDE:**

Microsoft Visual Studio 2005 to 2019, Visual Code.

### Databases:

SQL Server /2014/2016/2018, LINQ, Lamda.

#### MuleSoft:

MuleSoft 4.3.0, DataWeave 2.0, Cloudhub, JDK 1.8, Anypoint Studio 7.9.0.

### Azure services:

Azure Function App, Azure Storage Account, Azure SQL Server.

### Client & Server Side:

JavaScript, JQuery, Typescript & NodeJS.

### Repositories:

SVN, TFS, Azure Devops Pipeline.

### **Working Experience:**

- ♦ Worked as Senior Software developer in Mobile Programming, Chennai from April 2023 to July 2023.
- ♦ Worked as Senior Software developer in New Dream data Systems, Trichy from Nov 2017 to Feb2023.
- ♦ Worked as software developer in DSM soft, Trichy from Oct 2015 to Sep 2017.
- ♦ Worked as a Trainer/Software Developer in Ilife Technologies from June 2014 to August 2015.
- ♦ Worked as a Programmer in Aarovin Technologies from May 2013 to June 2014.

### PROJECT DETAILS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Mobile Programming, Chennai Senior Software Developer Client: LifeAlert Portal

**April 2023 – July 2023** 

Life Alert is a medical alert system specifically designed to protect seniors and all family members in a home health emergency. Life Alert services can help seniors remain independent and possibly avoid a retirement home by sending help fast in the event of a medical, fall, shower, and home emergencies. Senior health and longevity is as simple as a push of button allowing independent seniors to live alone without ever being alone.

As the creator of the, "Help, I've fallen and I can't get up!" company, Life Alert's medical alert system provides emergency help 24/7 even if you can't reach a phone and peace of mind to family members for medical alert emergency responses.

Tools & Technologies: C#, ASP.Net, SQL 2016, .NET 4.5 Visual Studio 9.

## Roles & Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis.
- Design the optimized implementation of the requirement.
- Implement the functionality in terms of coding.
- Unit test and fix the bugs/issues.
- Helped the development team to implement the detailed business requirements in the Project.
- Assisted by Development and Testing teams in troubleshooting and resolving issues.

# Newdream Data Systems, Trichy Senior Software Developer Client: NCIC, GMIC

Jan 2020 - Feb 2023

Horizon is dealing with Different kind of Insurance. They have deal different product like PA, HO, FO, DF, BOP. They have follow the ALL\*Points systems its means helps you manage your policy administration life cycle from beginning to end. The result? Faster time-to market, improved channel management, and larger books of business. This enables carriers to get to market faster, reduce core systems budgets and deliver better services. Horizon's ALL\*Points Policy Administration Solution System consolidates disjointed operational systems into one state-of-the-art platform to provide benefits to insurance carrier's internal operations and external agents and insured's.

**Tools & Technologies :** VB .Net, ASP.Net, SQL 2016, .NET 4.5, J-Query, Paymentus, lexisnexis, Authorize.Net, TFS, Visual Studio 9.

### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Implemented client requirement. Sent the code to review, once code review done. Check Incode to TFS.
- Communicate with the client and get the clarification on the unclear information through email.

- Integrated new third party application like Payments.
- Fix the bugs/issues then Unit test and prepare the document.
- Log the hours in Bill4Time and Basecamp.

# **Newdream Data Systems, Trichy Senior Software Developer**

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Client: CTE

CTE Project using Mulesoft Integration Platform as a three layer API (Experience, Process and System) to transform the data.

CTE is taking the value from UPTAKE API (Third Party) and doing the transformation and finally sending to Salesforce Marketing Cloud.

UPTAKE API is providing the Customer Opportunity Headers, Quote Headers details and performing the transformation and stored it in the Salesforce location.

Post transformation the data is going to JMS queue and sending into the Salesforce Marketing Cloud usingqueue machanisam.

Tools & Technologies: MuleSoft 4.3.0, DataWeave 2.0, SFMC, Splunk, Uptake API, Cloudhub, JDK1.8, Anypoint Studio 7.12.0, Postman

### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Requirement Analysis.
- Design the optimized implementation of the requirement.
- Implement the functionality in terms of coding.
- Unit test and fix the bugs/issues.
- Helped the development team to implement the detailed business requirements in the Project.
- Assisted by Development and Testing teams in troubleshooting and resolving issues.
- Deploying the code in Cloud-hub environment

# **Newdream Data Systems, Trichy Senior Software Developer**

July 2022 - Dec 2022

Client: DataACS

Implemented the automation project for doing CRUD operation in JIRA Story, Epic, Task and Defect Fetch the Records based on Sprint and Store the data for Report generation using Node JS,

Tools & Technologies: VS Code, JIRA, Node JS

### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Requirement Analysis.
- Design the optimized implementation of the requirement.
- Implement the functionality in terms of coding.
- Unit test and fix the bugs/issues.
- Assisted by Development and Testing teams in troubleshooting and resolving issues. Release the Application to Dev, Test and Production Environment.

# **Newdream Data Systems, Trichy Senior Software Developer**

July 2019 - Aug 2021

Client: NDDS (Task Track Allocation)

Task Track Application is used to track Status and Allocated Task Details for Employee. Each Employee has unique Login Id.We track Nds Sprint Based Task Details. Four Kinds of Roles are involved .Each and Every role has unique accessibility and response ability.

Employee has create new task and update the existing task details like task status, assigned to whom, Notes and Time.Its used to track Sudden Task details and affected task details.We can view Today Entered worked Hrs details in Task list page. Using Time Report we can view total Hrs details filtered by project based overall spending Hrs , Mantis based and Employee based overall spending Hrs details.

Tools & Technologies: C#, Asp .net core 2.0, Html, SQL Server 2014,VS Code (v1.23.0),Angular

(v6), Entity Framework, Lambda Expression.

### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis.
- Design the optimized implementation of the requirement.
- Using Jenkins deploy the different application in different environment and send the notificationemail for deployment.
- Fix the bugs/issues then Unit test and prepare the document.
- Release the Application to Dev, Test and Production Environment.

### **Client: NDDS (Intranet)**

Convert Organization Intranet site static HTML application to Dynamic Angular 6 application.

**Tools & Technologies :** C#, Asp .net core 2.0, Html, SQL Server 2014,VS Code (v1.23.0),Angular(v6),Entity Framework, Lambda Expression.

# Roles & Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis.
- Design the optimized implementation of the requirement.
- Implemented Database Design.
- Fix the bugs/issues then Unit test and prepare the document.
- Release the Application to Dev, Test and Production Environment.

# **Client: NDDS (Business Tracking)**

Manage Particular Organization All Business Details like Invoice, expense details, project details, client details etc. Implementing two different login Admin and manager. Implemented Ag-Grid concept this concept used to Without Refresh you can Insert, Update and Soft Delete the data.

**Tools & Technologies :** C#, Asp .net core 2.0, Html, SQL Server 2014,VS Code (v1.23.0),Angular(v6),Entity Framework, Lambda Expression, Ag-Grid.

## Roles & Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis.
- Design the optimized implementation of the requirement
- Implemented Database Design
- Fix the bugs/issues then Unit test and prepare the document.
- Release the Application to Dev, Test and Production Environment.

## Newdream Data Systems, Trichy Software Developer Client: Answer Health

Nov 2018 - July 2019

Working with Health Care Provider Login. In document upload process we implement the scheduler process. It's fully based on Health Care domain.

**Tools & Technologies :** C#, ASP.Net, SQL 2014,.NET 4.5,Angular JS (v1.x),Entity Framework, Linq, Lambda Expression.

### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Implemented client requirement. Sent the code to review, once code review done. Check Incode to SVN.
- Communicate with the client and get the clarification on the unclear information throughemail.
- Implement the functionality in terms of coding.
- Helped the development team to implement the detailed business requirements in the Project.

- Fix the bugs/issues then Unit test and prepare the document.
- Release the Application to Dev, UAT and Production Environment.

# Newdream Data Systems, Trichy Software Developer Client: Retire-IT

Nov 2017 - Dec 2018

Retire-IT was founded by a Harvard-educated recycling executive after witnessing the vulnerabilities first-hand. Organizations take enormous efforts to protect private data.

Chain-of-custody is the foundation for required for regulatory compliance. Don't be misled into a false sense of security. This isa migrate the product from legacy technology

Upgrade the .net framework 4.0 to 4.6.1 and implement the service now web api process.

Tools & Technologies: C#, ASP.Net, SQL 2014, .NET 4.0, J-Query, JavaScript, Telerik Controls.

### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Implemented client requirement. Sent the code to review, once code review done. Check Incode to SVN.
- Communicate with the client and get the clarification on the unclear information through email.
- Implement the functionality in terms of coding.
- Having knowledge about asset disposal domain concepts.
- Fix the bugs/issues then Unit test and prepare the document.
- Release the Application to Dev, Test and Production Environment.

# DSM Soft, Trichy Software Developer

Oct 2015 - Oct 2017

# Client: Land and Property Information (LPI)

The Scope of this system is to provide a customized solution on top of QGIS/ PostgreSQL(PostGIS) for capturing the information like parcels, roads, control marks, reference marks, etc., provided in the land title plans(scanned TIFF file) and convert those features to LandXML format which is used for developing a digital plan processing system that includes the preparation and lodgement of land title plans. The further use of this converted data, would be Data interchange from a Surveyor to Client as part of an ePlan lodgement of a new deposited plan and Data interchange when receiving existing digital plan data from Client.

### Tools & Technologies: VB.Net, Postgre Sql (PostGIS), Qgis, .NET 3.5

### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Covert micro-station code into Qgis application
- Co-Ordinate with the team and develop each task.
- Implemented client requirement. Sent the code to review, once code review done. Check Incode to SVN.
- Communicate with the production team and get the clarification on the unclear informationthrough email.
- Having knowledge about asset disposal domain concepts.
- Fix the bugs/issues then Unit test and prepare the document.

### **EDUCATION**

- ♦ MCA from Urumu dhanalakshmi College (2010 -13) Bharathidasan University Trichy
- ❖ BSC (Computer Science) from Urumu dhanalakshmi College (2007-10) Bharathidasan University Trichy
- riangle HSC from The Girls Higher Secondary School Srirangam (2005 07) Trichy.
- SSLC from Savitri Vidyasala Hindu Girls Higher Secondary School (2005) Trichy.

# Personal Details:

FATHER'S NAME: K.SHANMUGAM

HUSBAND NAME: K. RAJESH
DATE OF BIRTH: 15-Feb-1990
NATIONALITY: INDIAN
GENDER: FEMALE

MARITAL STATUS: MARRIED

LANGUAGES KNOWN: TAMIL, ENGLISH

# Declaration:

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place Yours Faithfully,

Chennai (S. Ezhilarasi)